Contact

8433597045 (Home) fazal.wiz@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/fazal-khan-06108547 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Machine Learning
Time Series Analysis
Data Science

Languages

English

Marathi

Hindi

Certifications

Learning the R Tidyverse

SAS Base 9.2

Data Analysis with Pandas & Python

Business Analytics: Forecasting with

Trended Baseline Smoothing

Business Analytics: Forecasting with

Exponential Smoothing

Publications

DIVISIBILITY & DIVISION BY 9

Fazal Khan

Associate Manager , Analytics & Data Science at Accenture Bengaluru

Summary

A Data Mining and Predictive Analytics Professional with ~9 years of work experience in the area of Statistical Modeling, Current Practitioner in Campaign analytics, Data Science, Machine Learning and Text Mining and Sentiment Analysis.

Specialized into the domain of Forecasting- Linear, Non-Linear, and ensemble including complex forecasting algorithms for time series Data. Ability to understand and implement complex algorithms like Neural Network(NN), support vector machine (SVM) and Machine Learning (ML) in Advanced Predictive Analytics.

Statistical Tools: SPSS, SAS, MINITAB

Languages: R, Python

Data Science: Machine Learning, Statistical Modeling, Data Analysis

Currently Learning: Spark & Algorithms

Analytical Techniques: Linear Regression, Segmentation-CHAID, Time Series Forecasting, Multiple Linear Regression, Logistic Regression, Decision Trees, Support Vector Machines, Gradient Descent, Neural Networks, KNN, LDA, PCA

Experience

Accenture

Associate Manager , Analytics & Data Science August 2018 - Present (2 years 1 month)

Mumbai Area, India

Tech Mahindra Senior Consultant July 2015 - July 2018 (3 years 1 month)

Page 1 of 3

Bengaluru Area, India

Campaign Analytics/Campaign Management:-

- Program and campaign effectiveness measurement through lift analysis and response modeling
- Campaign ROI Analysis
- Creating & analyzing short metrics and long metrics for Liability campaigns happening through outbound channels

First Source Solutions Ltd Business Evaluation Analyst October 2012 - May 2014 (1 year 8 months)

- Forecasting Incoming Call Flow Volume and Average Handling Time (AHT) using Time series forecasting techniques
- Creation and Validation of ARIMA, ARIMAX Modeling, VAR and VARMAX Modeling
- Creation and Validation of Single, Double and Triple Exponential Smoothing Model and ensemble smoothing models by using SAS & Excel
- Ensure each Customer service group is working with the most efficient number of staff by generating Optimization models
- Accurate forecasts of headcount requirements and engaging centres to recruit to the appropriate number of staff in a just-in-time manner.
- Ongoing validation of forecasting methodologies and models to ensure forecast accuracy is maintained & improved.

Tata Consultancy Services
Business Analyst
May 2010 - October 2012 (2 years 6 months)
Bangalore

- As Part of Analytics and Insights Transition team successfully helped the process transitioned from North America to Bangalore Center
- Provided Support in solving queries on SAS for the onshore team on continuous basis after transition
- Prodived SME support to offshore team in handling queries, prepareing training modules, delivering training on process
- Owning and impplementing process improvement ideas for effective usage of resources and time in terms of Automating processes.

Education

Indian Business Academy

Master of Business Administration (MBA), Finance and Marketing \cdot (2008 - 2010)

Jagadamba Mahavidyalaya Bachelor of Science (BSc), Mathematics · (2001 - 2004)

Smt.Ushabai Deshmukh Jr College 12th, Mathematics · (1999 - 2001)